var myQuestions = [
  {
    question: "1. Ali withdrew  \\({SAR}~{300}\\) from his bank's ATM. He \
    also purchased a  table for \\({SAR}~{120.87}\\) in cash \
    and paid \\({SAR}~{85.15}\\) for food supplies. He then used debit \
    card to pay for \\({SAR}~{450.50}\\) in cleaning supplies and \
    \\({SAR}~{86.27}\\) for electrical repairs. What amount was in Ali's \
    account if it had a balance of \\({SAR}~{1,340.21}\\) at the start \
    of the day?",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{297.42}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{237.10}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{533.44}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{503.44}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'a'
  },
 
  {
    question: "2. Jawad deposited his \\({$1,890.50}\\) paycheck and withdrew \
    \\({$295}\\). He also made two debit card purchases for \\({$152.87}\\) and \
    \\({$168.98}\\) in cash. If he started the day with a bank balance of \
    \\({$3,540.42}\\), what was his balance at the end of the day? ",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{8,595.07}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{1,033.07}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{4,814.07}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{5,457.77}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'c'
  },

  {
    question: "3. A retailer recoded these transactions in August for Hassan's account: \
    <ul>August 01 - balance forwarded \\({SAR}~{6,321}\\)</ul> \
    <ul>August 08 - Invoice #38 for \\({SAR}~{3,132}\\)</ul> \
    <ul>August 14 - payment for \\({SAR}~{4,124}\\)</ul> \
    <ul>August 16 - Credit Memo #25 \\({SAR}~{88.50}\\)</ul> \
    <ul>August 30 - Invoice #75 \\({SAR}~{2,130}\\)</ul> \
    What was the account's balance on August 31?",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{6,730.05}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{7,370.50}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{7,547.50}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{5,271.50}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'b'
  },

  {
    question: "4. Saleh had a balance of \\({SAR}~{2,289.63}\\) in his \
    checking account. He wrote checks for \\({SAR}~{42.41}\\), \
    \\({SAR}~{128.45}\\), \\({SAR}~{19.98}\\), and \\({SAR}~{87.66}\\). His \
    deposit was \\({SAR}~{2,046.25}\\). What was his new balance? ",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{35.12}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{521.88}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{4,057.38}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{4,614.38}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'c'
  },

  {
    question: "5. On October 31, Rajeh's bank statement showed a balance of \
    \\({SAR}~{1,001.79}\\). His check register's balance was \\({SAR}~{718.29}\\). \
    While comparing the bank statement to the check register, Rajeh found a service charge \
    of \\({SAR}~{13.65}\\). Check 56 for \\({SAR}~{76.09}\\) had been recorded \
    in the check register as \\({SAR}~{67.09}\\). A deposit of \\({SAR}~{194.35}\\) made \
    on November 10 had not been recorded in the check register, and Check 31 \
    for \\({SAR}~{47.36}\\) had been recorded twice in the check register. \
    An EFT loan payment for \\({SAR}~{159.10}\\) also was not recorded in the \
    check register. A deposit of \\({SAR}~{350}\\) was recorded in the check register \
    but was made too late to appear on the bank statement. Outstanding checks \
    were 63 for \\({SAR}~{157.73}\\) and 64 for \\({SAR}~{415.81}\\). \
    Reconcile Rajeh's checking account.",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{937.35}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{778.25}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{1,080.25}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{1,061.75}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'b'
  },

  {
    question: "6. In one day, Abdulrahman deposited his \\({SAR}~{10,500}\\) paycheck \
    at an ATM and withdrew \\({$150}\\). He also made two debit card purchases \
    for \\({SAR}~{209.25}\\) and \\({SAR}~{72.50}\\). If he started the day \
    with a bank balance of \\({SAR}~{3,546.45}\\), what was his balance \
    at the end of the day?",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{13,614.70}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{6,521.80}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{10,068.25}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{12,079.10}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'a'
  },


  {
    question: "7. Ahmad made deposits of \\({SAR}~{850}\\) and \\({SAR}~{2,360}\\) \
    to his account. He wrote checks for \\({SAR}~{895}\\), \\({SAR}~{720}\\), \
    and \\({SAR}~{125.83}\\). His previous balance before these transactions \
    was \\({SAR}~{295.43}\\). Determine Ahmad's updated balance.",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{1,690.17}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{1,469.17}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{1,865.74}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{1,764.60}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'd'
  },

  {
    question: "8. When Anas got his bank statement on August 31, it showed \
    a balance of \\({SAR}~{1,419.49}\\), a service charge of \
    \\({SAR}~{28.20}\\) and \\({SAR}~{51}\\) credit in his favor for an \
    error the bank had made. Outstanding checks were \\({SAR}~{370.13}\\), \
    \\({SAR}~{83.92}\\), \\({SAR}~{25.61}\\), \\({SAR}~{104.88}\\). His \
    checkbook showed a balance of \\({SAR}~{812.15}\\) on August 31. \
    Reconcile his check register.",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{1,320.29}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{321.05}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{834.95}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{614.71}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'c'
  },

  {
    question: "9. Rajeh's check register balance on June 30 \
    was \\({SAR}~{1,548.53}\\). His June 30 bank statement balance \
    showed \\({SAR}~{1,462.25}\\). Checks outstanding were \
    \\({SAR}~{298.12}\\), \\({SAR}~{86.73}\\) and \\({SAR}~{105.03}\\). \
    A direct deposit of \\({SAR}~{978.64}\\) appeared in the bank \
    statement. The bank service charge for June was \\({SAR}~{25.80}\\) \
    and the interest earned was \\({SAR}~{31.25}\\). An outstanding \
    deposit of \\({SAR}~{1,560.25}\\) was too late to appear in the statment. \
    Reconcile his bank statement.",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{2,925.87}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{2,532.62}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{2,056.04}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{4,092.97}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'b'
  },

  {
    question: "10. Fahad's online account balances on Friday \
    morning were \\({SAR}~{621.10}\\) (checking) and \\({SAR}~{3,820.60}\\) (savings).\
    On Friday evening, he plans his EFT transactions through the weekend. The \
    weekend bills include car loan \\({SAR}~{950}\\), electric bill \
    \\({SAR}~{454.05}\\) and water bill \\({SAR}~{115.15}\\). He plans \
    to make a \\({SAR}~{300}\\) ATM withdrawal from checking account \
    on Saturday morning. What must be the balance if he plans to have \
    a minimum balance of \\({SAR}~{500}\\) in his checking account?",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{2,319.20}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{1,819.20}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{1,698.10}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{2,940.30}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'a'
  },

  {
    question: "11. Hassan's bank statement balance on January 31 was \
    \\({SAR}~{12,475.40}\\). On the same date, his check register balance \
    was \\({SAR}~{10,320.15}\\). The bank statement showed a check printing \
    charge of \\({SAR}~{80.05}\\) and interest earned of \\({SAR}~{21.24}\\). \
    The checkbook showed three outstanding checks No. 98 for \
    \\({SAR}~{1,735.19}\\), No. 99 for \\({SAR}~{180.81}\\), and a \
    direct deposit on transit for \\({SAR}~{452.19}\\). Also, a check \
    for \\({SAR}~{750.25}\\) was recorded in the company's book \
    twice. Reconcile Hassan's check register.",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{10,739.27}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{11,725.21}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{11,011.59}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{10,261.34}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'c'
  },

  {
    question: "12. Manal's bank statement has a balance of \\({SAR}~{1,515.65}\\). It \
    has outstanding deposits of \\({SAR}~{150.6}\\) and two outstanding \
    checks amounting to \\({SAR}~{114.41}\\) and \\({SAR}~{87.52}\\). A \
    check for \\({SAR}~{23.34}\\) was recorded twice in the bank statement and credit \
    adjustment for \\({SAR}~{12.45}\\) was applied by the bank. \
    Calculate the reconciled amount.",
    answers: {
      a: '\\({SAR}~{1,602.77}\\)<br>',
      b: '\\({SAR}~{1,453.43}\\)<br>',
      c: '\\({SAR}~{1,464.32}\\)<br>',
      d: '\\({SAR}~{1,500.11}\\)'
    },
    correctAnswer: 'd'
  },
];

var quizContainer = document.getElementById('quiz');
var resultsContainer = document.getElementById('results');
var submitButton = document.getElementById('submit');

generateQuiz(myQuestions, quizContainer, resultsContainer, submitButton);

function generateQuiz(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer, submitButton){

  function showQuestions(questions, quizContainer){
    var output = [];
    var answers;
    for(var i=0; i<questions.length; i++){
      answers = [];
      for(choices in questions[i].answers){

        answers.push(
          '<label>'
            + '<input type="radio" name="question'+i+'" value="'+choices+'">'+ choices + '. '+ questions[i].answers[choices] + 
            '</label>'
            +'<br>'
        );

      }
      output.push(
        '<div class="question">'  + questions[i].question + '</div>' + '<div class="answers">'  + answers.join('') + '<br>' + '</div>'
      );
    }
    quizContainer.innerHTML = output.join('');

  }


  function showResults(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer){
    var answerContainers = quizContainer.querySelectorAll('.answers');
    var userAnswer = '';
    var numCorrect = 0;
  
    for(var i=0; i<questions.length; i++){

      userAnswer = (answerContainers[i].querySelector('input[name=question'+i+']:checked')||{}).value;
      if(userAnswer===questions[i].correctAnswer){

        numCorrect++;
        answerContainers[i].style.color = 'green';
      }
      else{
        answerContainers[i].style.color = 'red';
      }
    }
    resultsContainer.innerHTML = numCorrect + ' out of ' + questions.length + " or " + (numCorrect/questions.length * 100).toFixed(2) + "%";
  }


  showQuestions(questions, quizContainer);
  
  submitButton.onclick = function(){
    showResults(questions, quizContainer, resultsContainer);
  }

}
